谢谢你的捐赠
Oh,thank you so much for the donation.
我希望我能帮到更多
I wish I could do more,
只是一堆过时的旧衣服
it's just a bunch of old, outdated clothes.
一定都很不错
Oh,sure it's great.
3个星期前 我们的邻居兰德家
3 weeks ago, our neighbours, the Rand's
在一场大火中失去了房子和一切
lost their house and everything they own in a fire.
幸运的是没人受伤
Foetunately nobody was hurt.
更幸运的是 有他们的朋友
And fortunately, their friends,
就是我身边这位神奇女侠
was wonder woman, over here.
我可不是神奇女侠
I'm hardly wonder woman.
她动员了整个街区为他们捐赠衣服
She mobilized the community to donate clothes,
家具以及日常用品
furniture, appliances.
以助他们开始在新家的生活
All to help them start over in their new rental.
-房子是你找的 -我不是神奇女侠
- Which you found them. - I'm no wonder woman.
援助兰德计划是她的主意
Rand-aid was her idea.
"援助兰德计划" 那囧名可不是我起的
It wasn't my idea to call it "Rand-aid."
好吧
Okay, fine.
我是神奇女侠
I'm wonder woman.
可怕的灾难
Terrible tragedy.
他们是我们最亲密的朋友
They're our closest friends.
也就认识而已
We know them.
曼尼和他们家儿子罗本关系很铁
Uh, Manny and their son Reuben are tight.
事实上 他们家有个衣柜是我安装的
In fact, I put in one of their closets.
我不是说有多了不起
Not that it matters,
但那是火灾中唯一幸存的东西了
but it was the only structure to survive the fire.
上帝啊 不要提"火"那个词
Por favor, don't even say that word!
在我们国家 如果房子被烧毁
In my country it is considered very, very bad luck
那就意味着背到极点
when your house burns down.
他们离我们就一个街区远
They lived a block away from us.
到处都是烟雾
Smoke was everywhere.
我很难过 好几天都没睡
I was so upset, I couldn't sleep for days.
当然 米奇尔也不准我吃药
Of course, Mitchell won't let me take anything.
小卡 我们都知道原因吧
Well, Cam, we both know why.
有些人吃了那药会梦游
Some people have been known to sleepwalk
甚至在梦中开车
or even sleep drive on that medication.
小卡的问题要严重的多
Cam's reaction is much worse.
哦 哦 哦 上帝啊
Oh! Ohh! Oh, god.
我梦中扮小丑
I sleep clown.
老爸 你是在要自己的老命啊
Dad, you're gonna kill yourself.
我能行 我们还有安排
I got it! We're on a schedule here.
我还得去把卡车开过来
I still have to pick up the truck.
如果你不想让他搬东西
If you want him to stop lifting things,
就都放进杂物袋里
put all this in grocery bags
然后把电视调到足球频道
and turn the TV on to a football game.
把电话从我身上拿走
Oh! Take this phone away from me!
怎么了
Why?
我们公司最棒的两个经纪人另起炉灶了
Two of our best brokers left to start their own agency,
办公室流言蜚语四起
and the office gossip is flying.
我今天只想关注兰德一家的事
But I want today to be about the Rands...
一旦我开始听电话 哦 上帝啊
And if I have this-- oh, my god!
那两个家伙还带走了两个秘书和管子兄
Those guys took two secretaries and the tube dude with them!
管子兄是谁
Who's the tube dude?
就是那引人注目 迎风飘舞的家伙
You know, the blowy guy that attracts all the attention.
像这样...
This guy...
懂了 我见过他的
Ah, si, I've seen him.
他这样下来 然后这样摇摆
He goes down over there, and then he shakes up.
-再这样下来 -差不多就这样
- And goes down in there, and then... - You almost got it.
又这样下去
And then goes down.
抱歉 我们本该早些到的
Hi, hi, sorry. We would have been here sooner,
可我老公出门前不停换衣服
But this one had a wardrobe crisis.
那可是个很严肃的场合
You know, it's a somber occasion,
而我的上衣都太喜庆了
and all my tops are too joyful.
-你可不想遇到我们的问题 -不
-You do not want our problems. -No.
-杰 我来帮你 -不 我行
- Oh, here, Jay, let me help. - No, I got it.
-我的背 -爸
- Aah! My back! - Dad!
不 杰 你学得不像
No, Jay, that's not quite it.
知道吗 仿佛有一股风贯穿你全身
Remember, you got air blowing through you,
所以更像这样
So it's more like...
然后随风 起舞
And then out. And then out.
不要管我 我很好
Leave me alone. I'm fine.
我得去开那辆卡车
I've gotta pick up that truck.
我愿意去开那辆卡车
I'd be happy to get the truck.
算了吧 那卡车挺大的
I don't think so. It's a pretty big truck.
哦 难道还能大过
Oh. Is it--is it bigger than the combine
我从12岁就开始驾驶的联合收割机
I've been driving since I was 12 years old?
或是那个巨型收割型拖拉机
Or the Widrow tractor with the Macdon header
就是我开去参加高中毕业舞会 并平行停车的那个吗
that I drove to and parallel parked at my high school prom? Hmm?
-至少那晚地面被刺"破"了 -我听到了
- At least something got plowed that night. - Heard that!
你妹的
Oh, son of bitch!
你的腰部正在痉挛呢 杰
Your low back is in spasm, Jay.
我可以给你做个按摩
I can massage that out for you.
我很好
I'm fine.
老爸 你会错过极大的享受哦
Dad, you don't know what you're missing.
菲尔简直就是魔法师
Phil is a magician.
还是个有执照的按摩师
And a licensed masseur.
在我投身房地产业之前
Before I heard the siren song of residential real estate,
我可是按摩大师哦
I was bitten by the rub bug.
他真的很神奇
No, he's--he's amazing.
之前我腿上长了个包
I had this knot in my leg,
菲尔帮我按摩了两分钟就消了
Two minutes with Phil and it was gone.
不好意思 我觉得你可能比较习惯
I'm sorry, but I think you might have a higher tolerance
让男人的手在你身上乱摸
for a man's hands on your body than I do.
-您真会说话 -不要犯傻了
- Charming. - Ay, don't be an idiot.
让菲尔帮帮你吧
Let Phil help you.
好吧
Fine.
太棒了 我这就去准备房间
Great! I'll just go get the room ready.
你会为我双手的魔力感到吃惊的
I'll think you'll be surprised with what these hands can do.
是吗 你的双手能因为你和人打赌
Really? Can they drive a Bobcat skid-steer
就开着带草扒子的小推土机 穿越学校过道吗
with a bucket grapple through a school hallway on a dare?
我的双手不但可以 还成功了
Because these can and have.
可怜的罗本
Poor Reuben, huh?
不得不在12岁时就重建自己的生活
Having to rebuild his whole life at age 12.
是啊 太他妈背了
Yeah. That blows.
我明白我俩都被吓坏了
I know we're both shaken up,
不过还是要注意文明用语
but let's watch the language.
把这个放到安全的地方 这是给罗本的
Okay, put this in a safe place. It's for Reuben.
就是那种
It's one of those, um,
怎么说来着 那种塔卡塔卡响的
How do you say again, the takka-takka-takka...
是那种内置照相机的直升飞机吗
Is that the helicopter with the camera in it...
可以用手机控制的那种
that you control with your phone?
是我一直想买的那种吗
The one I asked for?
是的 房子被烧了
Okay, when your house burns down,
就得到个飞机做安慰
you get one of these.
不 我不是让你去烧房子啊
No, don't burn your house down.
罗本是有多幸运啊
How lucky is Reuben?
太幸运了
So lucky.
我建议把它拿出来
You know what? I say we take this thing out
瞧瞧它是怎么飞的
and see how she flies.
不太好吧 这是我妈妈买给罗本的
I don't know. My mom got it for Reuben.
我们就不能分享下他的玩具吗
Oh, so now he won't even share his toys?
他从不与人分享玩具
He never does.
让那家伙去死吧
Screw that guy!
就是
Yeah!
真是近墨者黑
You're a terrible influence.
黑黑更健康
You need me.
克莱尔 考虑到你可能还要放东西进去
Claire, in case you want to add something,
我把这箱裙子放在外面
I put the box of dresses outside
都是爪七爪八的东西[杂七杂八]
And this is the box of snicker snackers.
谢谢
Mm. Thanks.
米奇尔 我们的确该放点什么进去
Mitchell, we did have something to add to this box of, um...
爪七或者是爪八
Snicker snackers.
怎么了
What?
英语不是她的母语
English is not her first language.
她也只是想要帮忙
She's just trying to help.
米奇尔 得了吧 你别这样
Mitchell, come on. You can't do that.
你不能突然改变规矩啊
You can't just change the rules.
我们常干这事的啊
This is what we do.
每当歌洛莉亚发出搞笑的口音
When Gloria says something silly,
我们就会在背后取笑她
we innocently laugh behind her back.
她这周过得不顺 好吗
She's had a rough week, all right?
她非常担心蒂娅·玛利娅·塞西莉娅的手术
She's really worried about Tia Maria Cecilia and that surgery.
而且她上普拉提课时还把手机丢了
Oh, and then she lost her cell phone at pilates.
-你怎么知道的 -我们经常一起喝咖啡
- How do you know this? - We have coffee.
经常哈
Oh. Have?
你们什么时候经常私下聚会的
So when did this become, like, a thing?
有问题吗 我们是朋友 我喜欢她
What's the big deal? We're friends. I like Gloria.
没什么大不了的
Uh, it's no big deal.
我对她毫无意见 只不过
I have nothing against her, I just think--oh!
这下可好
Mm. All right.
在你指责我之前 我得说 那花瓶是我送她的
So before you get all judge-y, I gave her that vase.
那是我先送给你的
After I gave it to you.
你非得穿这件T恤吗
You couldn't part with that t-shirt?
我喜欢
I love this shirt.
你不必非得打扮成现在这样
You know, you don't have to look the way you look.
安波儿·兰德的衣服都被火灾烧没了
Amber Rand lost all her clothes in a fire,
可她得到了改头换面的机会
but she gets to build herself a new wardrobe.
让我把你的衣服也烧了吧
Let me burn your clothes.
孩子们 快下来 还有一堆活要干呢
Girls, get down here. There's a lot of work to do.
-她要发飙了 -接下来怎么办你懂吧
- Ugh. She's in a mood. - You know what we have to do, right?
-你不配当我的亲姐姐 -我讨厌你
- There's no way you're my real sister! - I hate you!
-难以置信你居然 -你个自私鬼
- I can't believe you would ever-- -You're the most selfish--
到此为止 我受不了了
Okay, that's it! I cannot take the fighting!
哪儿凉快上哪儿待着去
Just get out of the house.
这招屡试不爽
Works every time.
知道吗 我还不想开卡车呢
You know, I don't even wanna drive the truck anymore
虽然在农场那会儿
Even though on the farm I was--
别再提农场的事了
I can't take another farm story.
-万岁 -你得找个人和你一起
- Yay! - You might wanna take someone with you.
那车停在那儿都半年了
The thing's been parked there six months.
你需要洗洗车 打扫一下蜘蛛网
You're gonna want to hose it down, sweep for spiders.
好消息 姑娘们 跟小卡舅夫一起去
Good news, girls. You're going with Uncle Cam.
真棒
Yay!
我肯寻求菲尔的帮助 一定是疼得忍无可忍了
The pain must have been pretty bad if I was asking Phil for help.
他使尽浑身解数想得到我的肯定
His need for my approval is exhausting.
十年来 我就麻烦他干过一件事
In ten years, I've asked him for one thing--
接通我的无线打印机
To hook up my wireless printer.
结果他一直念叨这事
He still won't shut up about it.
打印机运作还正常吧
How's that printer working out for you?
还爱用那打印机是吗
Still loving that printer, eh?
如果你的打印机坏了
You know, if your printer breaks from here,
-我能用电话远程修好它 -真的吗
- I can fix it on my phone. - Can you?
当然 不过没这必要
I can, but I don't need to,
因为我已经把它修得完美无瑕了
Because I fixed it forever.
哪怕一次也好 我真希望
Just once, I wish he wouldn't make
他不要这么小题大做
such a big deal about everything.
来吧
Okay.
现在请宽衣解带 拿毛巾盖住屁股
Now just disrobe and place the towel over your buttocks.
开着大卡车
Riding the open road
在路上飞驰
in a big rig like this
还真能激发男性那惊人的食欲啊
sure can work up a man's powerful appetite.
我们刚开出五个街区远
We've gone five blocks.
-你到底吃不吃汉堡 -我倒是没意见
- Do you want a burger or not? - I could eat.
艾丽克斯
Hey, Alex,
也许等会小卡舅夫能把他的帽子借你
maybe Uncle Cam will let you borrow his hat later.
毕竟你已经是一副纯爷们的打扮
You know, since you dress like a dude.
我就喜欢这样
I like the way I dress.
小卡舅夫 作为她未来的舞会男伴
Uncle Cam, as her future prom date,
你能跟她谈谈吗 你最懂时尚了
will you please talk to her? You know fashion.
首先 你们俩各有自身的美丽之处
First of all, you're each beautiful in your own way,
但你们都得排第二位
but you're both playing for second,
因为开着卡车的我才最性感
because I'm too sexy for... this truck.
不得不承认 你开得出人意料的好
I have to say, you do drive it surprisingly well.
没错 谁能想到呢
Yeah, who would have thought?
出人意料?
Surprising?
基佬开卡车就很出人意料吗
What, that--that a gay man can drive a truck?
如果是杰那代人的想法 我还能理解
You know, I expect that kind of thinking from Jay's generation.
但是连90后也这么想吗
But from our future generation?
无法接受
No.
这里实在是挤爆了
Wow. This place got crowded.
你真是"卡"在中间了
Whoa. You're really wedged in there.
需要我们给你导向吗
You want us to help guide you out?
如此一问
That question--
充满仇恨犯罪的意味
It was like a hate crime.
抱歉
Sorry!
你靠这边太近了
Hey, you're really close on this side.
我知道
Yeah, I see it.
-小心 -我已经够小心的了
- Careful! - I'm being careful.
犯得着大喘气吗
Gasping? Really?
至于把手握那么紧吗 又不是要俯冲
Holding hands? We're not in a nosedive.
好吧 我服了
Okay, you know what,
如果你们乐意 那就下车给我导向吧
if it would make you feel better, get out and guide me.
来吧 快点
Okay, come on. Let's go.
请别对我大喊大叫 可这车门打不开
Please don't yell at me, but there's not enough room.
好吧 从我这爬下去
Okay, climb over.
你没事的
You're fine.
知道吗 土著人坚信烧鼠尾草的香气
You know, the native Americans believe that burning sage
能让负面能量消散
kept bad energy away.
想想他们可悲的下场吧
How'd that work out for 'em?
快来帮我按背吧
Get to the back.
这就对了
That's the spirit.
多谢你了
Thank you.
我得确认下这油已达到37度了[体温]
I just need to make sure that the oil is a perfect 98.6.
没错 完美无瑕
And it is perfect.
现在 你先深呼吸
Now I want you to take a deep breath
让我引领你到达一个
and let me transport you to a land
名为放松圣域的地方
I call relaxistan.
怎么回事 滚下来
Oh, what the hell? Get off me.
我就知道这肯定糟...
I knew this was a terrible...
妈妈咪呀 爽死了
Oh, Mama Lucian, that's good.
想玩玩吗
So you wanna try it?
我也说不好 我还是觉得很内疚
I don't know. I'm still feeling guilty.
那本来是罗本的直升飞机
It's Reuben's helicopter.
就因为是他 我们才更该玩
Reuben is the whole reason we should be doing this.
他就是《世事难料》中那活生生的例子
He's barely living proof that life can change in a second.
人生得意须尽欢 今朝有酒今朝醉
You gotta grab what you can when you can.
你究竟是对我施了什么魔法
What is this hold you have on me?
真棒
Wow.
很好 现在减速
Okay, now ease up.
我在减速 不管用啊
Okay, I'm easing up. Okay, it's not working.
曼尼 快控制住 它要飞走了
Get ahold of yourself, Manny! She's getting away!
-我控制不住了 -给我
- I can't--I... I can't hold her! - Give it to me!
紧急求救 紧急求救
Mayday! Mayday!
算了算了
Oh, well.
你什么意思 我妈会宰了咱俩的
What do you mean "Oh, well"? My mom's gonna kill us.
跟我有什么关系 是你在玩
Us? You were flying it.
我可是在阁楼整理箱子
I was in the attic packing boxes.
你得帮我把它找回来
You're gonna help me find it,
不然我就让你人间蒸发
or the next search will be for you.
我喜欢你这态度 平时你怎么不这样
I like this guy. Where's he been?
放松
Just relax.
疼了你就吱一声
Let me know if I'm hurting you.
你开玩笑吧 我都爽死了
Are you kidding me? It's fantastic.
我爱你
I love you.
按摩 我爱的是按摩
This! I love this!
当时脱口而出了
It just slipped out.
那是我对菲尔说过的最糟糕的三个字
Those are the worst three words I could say to Phil.
我当时默默祈祷他能就此跳过不提
I was just praying he would let it go
不要小题大做
And not make a big deal about it.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
事关重大
This is huge.
杰 抱歉
Jay, I'm sorry.
我失陪一下
I need a minute.
兔崽子
Son of a bitch!
兔崽子技术还真不错
Son of a bitch.
多好的衣服啊 曼尼干嘛不要了
Oh, these are fantastic. Why is Manny getting rid of them?
他说这些都过时了
He said that they were last season.
我以前也有条这样的裤子
I used to have a pair like these.
再也找不到这种款式的了
I can never find 'em anymore.
有个直销店有这款
Oh, there's an outlet store.
他们虽然没有成人码的
They don't have men's size,
不过我敢肯定男童装的最大号
but I'm sure the biggest size for boys
你也穿得下 我带你去
would fit you perfectly. I'll take you.
-好 约定了 -又要"约"会是吧
- All right. It's a date. - Oh. Another date.
克莱尔 我听说花瓶的悲剧了
Claire, I heard what happened with the vase,
你不用放在心上
but I don't want you to worry about it.
抱歉 我应该早点告诉你的
I'm so sorry. I should have told you about that sooner.
我还沉浸在火灾的震惊中
It just--I have really been shaken by this whole fire thing.
生命真是伤不起啊
You know, life is so fragile.
我懂的 就像花瓶一样脆弱
I know, like a vase.
你打我的小报告吗
You tattled on me?
她问起那事 我只能老实交代了
She asked me about it. What was I supposed to do?
你干嘛怪腔怪调的
Why are you making those cruel sounds with your mouth?
你还不明白吗
You don't see it?
你把歌洛莉亚当成妈了
You're turning Gloria into mom.
什么
What?
首先你全力维护她
First you got all defensive of her,
然后又向她打我的小报告
and then you tattled on me to her.
你对待我们的亲妈就是那样
That's exactly what you did with old mom.
现在你对后妈也来这一套
It's what you're doing with new mom.
好吧 我懂了
Okay, okay.
只有你才把我和歌洛莉亚之间的友谊
Only you could make my friendship with Gloria
看得那么邪恶
into something ugly.
别误会了 我觉得你俩挺甜蜜的
Don't get me wrong. I think it's sweet.
每个人都有些小怪癖 你是恋母情结
We've all got our thing. You have mommy issues.
我才没有恋母情结
I do not have mommy issues!
好 那我明天来接你
Okay. So I pick you up tomorrow,
一起去买你的大男孩裤裤
We go get you your big boy pants,
然后去吃冰激凌 如何
and then we go and get a little ice cream, okay?
绝配啊
Perfect.
我才不要听你瞎扯
I don't wanna hear it.
你还在难受吗
You still don't feel very good?
我对菲尔说了我爱他
I told Phil I loved him.
我是不小心说溜嘴的
It was an accident.
-你知道他对这种事的反应 -是啊
- You know how he gets with that stuff. - Ay, I know.
杰 刚才的事 我们待会再谈好吗
Jay, can I talk to you later about what just happened?
-行 -谢了
- Yeah. - Thanks.
哎呀 我把你背部按摩好了嘛
Jeez, I just worked that out.
你完蛋了
You're screwed.
今天对我来说 意义非凡
Today is the biggest day of my life.
放松
Just relax.
疼了你就吱一声
Let me know if I'm hurting you.
你开玩笑吧 我都爽死了
Are you kidding me? It's fantastic.
我爱你
I love you.
按摩 我爱的是按摩
This! I love this!
我的天
Oh, my god.
事关重大
This is huge.
杰 抱歉 我失陪一下
Jay, I'm sorry. I need a minute.
那两个辞职的哥们要我也辞职
The two guys who left the firm asked me to quit my job
和他们一起去当新公司的合伙人
and partner with them at the new agency.
天大的好机会啊
Big opportunity,
也是天大的风险
big risk,
他们要我今天就答复
And they need an answer by the end of the day.
在压力之下 我一般都会做些失控的事
I don't always make great decisions under presure.
那是啥玩意
What the hell is that?
草泥马[羊驼] 我抢到了最后一只
An alpaca. I got the last one.
拜托 把卡车移走
Come on! Move that truck!
我讨厌你
I hate you!
好 我和一桌子卡车司机打情骂俏了一番
Okay, so... I flirted with a table of truckers
他们终于愿意帮忙了
who have offered to help us.
不 不需要帮忙 我已经快成功了
No! No help! I've come too far!
是吗
Have you?
人家小饭店是不卖披萨的
Oh, hey! They don't sell pizzas at this restaurant!
非顾客不能在此非法停车
You parked here illegally!
祝贺你 先生 你丢尽了美国的脸
Congratulations, sir. You're destroying America.
现在我们后面没有车 快走 发动
Hey, there are no cars behind us. Go! Gun it!
没事 没事 大家别紧张
All right! All right! Everybody relax!
我们没事 没事
We're fine! We're fine!
-没事才怪 -我们都挤扁了
- We are not fine! - And we're all smooshed!
-吓死了 -而且还倾斜30度角仰望天空
- And we're scared! - And we're tilted at a 30-degree angle!
你个书呆子 我们又脏又累又迟到了
Nerd! And we're dirty and tired and late!
够了 你们保持安静好不好
Okay! Can you please just be quiet!
我们为什么不找人帮忙呢
Why couldn't we have just asked for help?
因为我要给你们上宝贵的一课
'cause I'm teaching you girls a very valuable lesson--
基佬不输直男 顶天立地好汉
That gay men can do anything straight men can do.
我们知道啊
Yeah, we know that.
你以为我们只认识你一个基佬吗
Do you think you're the only gay guy that we know?
对 我的足球教练就是基佬
Yeah. My soccer coach is gay,
儿科医生也是
Our pediatrician...
-我的拉丁文家教 -书呆子 我们的电工
- My latin tutor. - Nerd! Our electrician.
那我说我会开卡车的时候
Well, then why were you so surprised
你们怎么那么震惊
when I said I could drive a truck?
那不是因为你的性取向 而是因为你的性格
Not because you're gay, because you're you.
再说 你的确不会开
And by the way, you can't.
好吧 我向你们道歉
Okay, wow. I guess I owe you an apology.
我会错意了
I made a leap there.
因为人们对同志形象的陈旧认识
I'm just used to dealing with stereotypes.
我有点太过敏感了
I'm a little sensitive about it.
那是和我聊过天的卡车司机
Oh! There's the trucker that I talked to.
打扰一下 你好
Hey! Excuse me! Hi!
能帮我们一把吗
Could you give us a hand, please?
没问题呀 亲爱的
Sure thing, sweetie.
那人妖也能帮上忙吗
Oh, like she'll be able to help us.
老爹 真是难以想象啊
Boy, do you have the right idea.
总算从楼下的母子大重逢里
Could use a little break from the mother and child reunion
解脱出来了
going on down there.
别问
Don't ask.
米奇尔把歌洛莉亚当亲妈了 瞧 我说了
Mitchell's turning Gloria into mom. Bam! It's out.
你记得米奇尔和妈妈以前
You remember the way mom and Mitchell used to be
总沉浸在他们的两人小世界吗
in their private little club,
就他们俩 闲人勿进
Just the two of them, and no one else allowed in.
历史又在重演啊
Well... it's happening again,
但这一次 你老婆也有参与演出
But this time around, it's happening with your wife.
你真该下去看看他俩
You should see them down there.
要不是他俩太恶心 其实也挺可爱的
It would actually be adorable if it weren't so sick.
我只是
I just--
我觉得米奇尔都是成年人了
You know, I feel like Mitchell is a grown man,
都是当爹的人了
he has a child,
可还摆脱不了20年前的心理问题
and he's still working out some psychodrama from 20 years ago.
爸 能让我喝口啤酒不
Daddy, can I have a sip of your beer, please?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
米奇尔黏着妈妈 我就来投奔我爸
Mitchell cozies up to mom, I go running to daddy.
我才是把歌洛莉亚当成亲妈的人
I'm the one who's turning Gloria into mom,
明明我俩就一样大 真让人不安
which is really disturbing since we're the same age.
你比她大
You're older.
你憋了半天就吐槽这么一句吗
Oh. Oh, that's where we're gonna chime in?
你能快点不
Will you hurry up?
我在保存我的体力
I'm saving my strength
因为如果我们找不到那架直升机
Because if we don't find this helicopter,
我得逃往到加拿大去
I'm walking to Canada.
希望你喜欢高税收
Hope you like taxes.
瞧 那是我们的直升机
Hey! That's our helicopter!
是吗
Is it, now?
你有相关证明文件吗
I'm sure you have the proper documentation for that.
快还给我们 是我们的
Just give it back. It's ours.
你们是恶霸啊
You guys are bullies.
他们才当不了恶霸 是书呆子才对
They can't be bullies. They're nerds.
别分的那么细 我们可以是"恶霸书呆子"
Don't pigeonhole us. We can be both.
有什么问题吗
Is there an issue here?
小卡舅夫 我来搞定
Uncle Cam, I got this.
我的天啊 是艾丽克斯·邓菲
Oh, my god, it's Alex Dunphy.
好美啊
So awesome.
杠上了吗 小伙子们
Problem here, boys?
这些死宅男不肯把直升机还给我们
These geeks won't give us back our helicopter
那是我们从罗本那儿抢来的
that we took from Reuben.
是这样吗 亚伯拉罕
Is that right, Abraham?
我的天啊 她知道你的大名
Oh, my god. She knows your name.
直升机 还来
Helicopter, please.
我爱你
I love you.
刚刚什么情况
What just happened?
你有帅哥追 我有宅男捧
You have your fans, I have mine.
有朝一日 帅哥都得为宅男打工
Some day, your fans are going to work for my fans.
那个 歌洛莉亚
Oh, um, Gloria,
你介意我和米奇尔单独聊聊吗
Do you mind if I talk to Mitchell alone for a minute?
没事的 我已经知道你说什么了
It's okay. I already know what you said,
我觉得那也太离谱了
And I think it's crazy.
米奇尔没有把我当他的妈咪啊
Mitchell is not making me his mommy.
我知道他没有 但我想是我把你当妈了
No, I know. He's not, but I think that I might be.
好吧 现在你更是疯话连篇了
Okay, now you're going really, really crazy,
因为我可是比你还年轻哟
because I am younger than you.
就年轻14个月 算了吧
Mm, by 14 months, so let's settle down.
你今天怎么回事
What is going on with you today?
我 好吧 我终于想明白了
I... all right, I'm working this out as I go.
我觉得我今天见到
I think maybe seeing
你和歌洛莉亚那么亲密
you get all buddy-buddy today with Gloria
让我觉得想当年
made me feel like it did
你和妈妈也如此 所以...
when you were with mom, and--and...
我不知道 我觉得我被你们抛弃了
I don't know. I-I felt like the odd man out.
其实 对于你和爸爸的关系 我也是同样的感觉
Okay. Well, that--that's how I used to feel with you and dad.
我知道 我知道 我们各自选择阵营
I know. I know. We--we chose teams,
就连爸妈离婚时也一样
even during the divorce. It...
听我说 最近几年里
Okay, the last couple years,
你和我是最亲密的
you and I have been our own team.
明白吗 所以我不希望我们姐弟俩疏远了
You know? And I don't want that to go away.
所以
So...
我想我今天有点被冷落的感觉
I guess I just felt a little left out today.
别说了
Shut up.
好吧 你们能不能换成抱箱子
Okay, can you two try hugging a box
好让你们可怜的后妈不那么辛苦
so that your poor mother doesn't have to do all the hard work?
歌洛莉亚 实在抱歉今天说的那些疯话
I am sorry, Gloria, about all the mom stuff today.
我只是 有个疯狂的想法
I just--I got this crazy idea
觉得你喜欢米奇尔胜过我
that you liked Mitchell better than me.
我的确更喜欢米奇尔
I do like Mitchell better than you.
什么
What?
哎呀 拜托
Ay, please.
你敢不敢诚实地告诉我
Are you going to honestly tell me
在这个家里你最喜欢我
that I'm your favorite person in this family?
在这个家 我甚至不算你最喜欢的哥伦比亚人吧
I'm not even your favorite Colombian in this family.
我是很想和你搞好关系
I would love to get closer to you.
你知道我电话
You have my number.
但是要早点打电话呦 很多人约我的
But call me quickly because I book up.
你们谁也没看见我啊
You never saw me.
你在这啊
There you are.
-我真的需要和你谈谈 -完全没那必要
- I really need to talk to you. - You really don't.
杰 拜托 是工作上的事
Jay, please. It's about work.
给你按摩的时候我收到一条短息
I got a text during your massage.
有一家新成立的公司请我去当合伙人
I've been offered a partnership in a new agency.
那不赖啊
Good for you!
我不确定
I'm not so sure.
我是说 那的确算是大升职
I mean, there's--there's a big upside,
但我现在有份稳定的工作
But I have a stable job right now.
我有3个孩子 至少有一个会上大学的
I have three kids, and at least one of them's going to college.
一不小心 3个都会上的
Worse case scenario, they all go.
那么 克莱尔是怎么想的
Well, what does Claire think?
我还没和她说呢 我想先跟你谈谈
I haven't told her yet. I wanted to talk to you first.
你有经验
You've done this.
其实 我觉得根本上其实只有一个问题
Well, I think that there's only really one question.
我是否准备好自己下海创业吗
Whether I'm ready to run my own company?
你很擅长与人打交道
Ah, you're great with people.
我们知道你是个很好的推销员
We know you're a good salesman.
你在经济不景气的时候 也让家人生活富足
You've managed to provide a good living in tough times.
那问题是什么 恰当的时机吗
Then what? Is this the right time?
永远都没有恰当的时机
Never a perfect time.
没准房子明天就烧了
House could burn down tomorrow.
问题是 你到底想不想这么做
Question is, do you want this?
想
Yeah.
想 我真想自己干
Yeah, I really want it.
那就赌自己一把
Then gamble on yourself.
我赌你赢
I'd gamble on you.
那我就干
I'm gonna do it.
那不就得了
There you go!
谢了 杰
Thanks, Jay.
听着 我知道你之前不太愿意做按摩
Hey, look, I know you were reluctant to get that massage,
但我觉得 现在是皆大欢喜了
but I think we can both agree it had a happy ending.
求你别说"欢喜"
Please don't say that.
如果我只能在火灾中带走一样物品
If I could only save one possession in a fire,
应该会救我的第一套高尔夫球杆
probably my first set of golf clubs.
是我老爸给我的
My old man gave 'em to me.
杰给我的结婚戒指
The engagement ring that Jay gave me
改变了我的一生
that changed my life.
莉莉的领养证书
Lily's adoption papers.
我本来也想说是领养证书
I was gonna say adoption papers.
既然你已经拿了 我就拿走我妈的菜谱
So I guess, then, I would say my mom's recipe book.
所有的家庭照片
All our family photos...
我都存在iPad里 那就拿iPad吧
which I keep on my iPad, so my iPad.
只要我的家人在身边
As long as I have my family,
我就什么都不需要了
I wouldn't need anything else.
太假了
Aw, man!
怎么了嘛
What?
你说的境界那么高
You say something like that,
让我们显得好渺小
it makes us all seem petty.
-就是 -其实
- Yeah. - Well...
我故意的
I know.
讨厌
Hiss!
小卡睡着了 我不想把他吵醒
Cam's sleeping. I don't wanna wake him.
他今天可悲催了
He's had a rough day.
那也没外公的卡车悲催
Not as rough as grandpa's truck.
多谢你们载我回家
Thank you so much for driving me.
我真的不想开那大卡车
I really didn't want to ride in that big rig.
难忘的经历啊 当时所有人都在按喇叭
It was amazing. Everybody was honking,
而且我还学了差不多五句脏话
And I learned, like, five new curse words.
大多都是小卡说的
Mostly from Cam.
真高兴今天能博得您二位千金一笑
Oh, I'm glad I could give you a laugh today.
我还不知道我在你们眼里
You know, I didn't know that's what I was to you people--
-就一笑料 -不是那样的 亲爱的
- a big joke. - No, honey, it wasn't like that.
我们不是故意的 小卡舅夫我们爱你
No, we really didn't mean-- uncle Cam, we love you.
得了吧 我要回去睡觉了
Save it. I'm going back to bed.
他那老毛病还没好啊
So he's still doing that?
是啊 不过我们正努力改呢
Yeah. Yeah, but we're working on it.